- [Instructor] We are now ready to set up our database
inside of our API, so let's get to it.
So let's close these files for now,
and what we're going to do is load the index.js
and I'm going to close the explorer
just to have a little bit more screen here,
and what I'm going to do now is import mongoose first,
which are going to be the tool that we're going to use
to do transactions with our MongoDB.
It simplifies the syntax versus doing straight command
to the Mongo server.
We're also going to import bodyparser.
We're going to import cors from cors,
and cors allows us to do transactions
with different domains.
So basically cross-transactional.
So if you're having issues doing specific transactions
with a backend, that's usually one of the issue.
You can read more on cors online
if you want to research it.
And we're going to set up our routes right away.
One thing that is certain is once we import our routes
inside the index.js file,
and we haven't set up any routes yet,
A, it's going to break the application,
but we'll get to that soon.
So I'm going to import from routes and soccerroutes.
Okay, now the next thing we're going to set
is our Mongo connection.
So I'm just going to write a little note
for your own purposes.
Mongo connection,
and I'm going to use mongoose with a promise,
which will be a global promise,
and then I'm going to connect
using that promise to our MongoDB.
And if you remember localhost,
you may need to put the port in certain cases,
but in most cases, it's going to know for a default
that it's the Port 27017.
So in this case, we don't have to put it.
And I'm going to create a soccerdb.
I'm also going to set my bodyparser right away.
I'm going to app use bodyparser, urlencoded.
So this is to parse what we're receiving from our request,
so to allow our request to pass through and parsed.
And then what we're going to use is json.
So we're going to set that up right here, json.
And then finally, we're going to set up our cors.
So app use cors and pass the routes to the app.
Perfect.
So let's go into our terminal.
So create a new terminal, and also you want to make sure
that the terminal you're running is in the backend again,
because if we do it ls, we're at the top directory.
So cd backend.
And if we run the server right now, it's going to break,
and the reason is because we have routes
that are passed through the app,
but our routes are not defined yet.
So if you run this, it's going to give you a bunch of errors.
So for the time being, if you want to run the server
and make sure everything runs properly
before we set up our routes,
all you have to do is comment this line here, save it,
and the server is running on port 4000,
that means that everything is running properly,
the connection to Mongo has worked,
so you're all good to go.